How an AK-47 Works
When trigger is pulled, 'hammer' releases and strikes firing pin.
Firing pin strikes 'bullet primer' which contains a compound that explodes to ignite gun powder.
Expanding gases force the 'gas piston' backward.
The 'bolt carrier' is forced back, ejecting casing.
'Bolt' pulls a new round from the magazine and inserts into barrel.
Bolt carrier also resets 'hammer' to starting position.
The 'sear' keeps hammer held in place until bolt carrier returns to position.
To fire in automatic, the 'selector' is moved to the middle position.
This holds the 'disconnector' back, keeping it from catching the hammer while trigger is pressed.
Modeling, texturing, and animation by Matt Rittman
Special thanks to: Kate Rittman (wife), Anson Call (college professor), and Nic McDougal (friend)
Created with Cinema 4D, Corona Renderer, and Adobe After Effects
This project was created solely for the purpose of illustration, and does not necessarily reflect the views or opinions of the designer.